Cloud just introduced this concept
Cloud公司刚刚引入了“
called agent skills. It might look
代理技能”这个概念。 它看起来可能很
complicated, but it's actually really
复杂，但实际上
simple ideas, but super powerful. And
理念非常简单，却非常强大。 而且
many things that it might be even bigger
很多方面都表明，它甚至可能
than MCP. So, a cloud core skill you can
比MCP更大。 因此，您可以将云核心技能
almost consider as a combination of both
视为两种技能的结合体：一是
a prompt instruction to teach agent how
提示性指令，用于教代理如何
to do certain skills, as well as a list
执行某些技能；二是
of assets and tools like predefined
资产和工具列表，例如预定义的
functions and templates guidelines to
功能和模板指南，以
make it produce more consistent result.
使其产生更一致的结果。
But two and assets are kind of optional.
但是两项资产是可选项。
It can be as simple as just one single
也可以很简单，只需要一个
prompt as well. For example, for the
提示即可。 例如，对于
brand guideline skill, it's literally
品牌指南技能，实际上
just one single prompt including very
只有一个提示，其中包含
specific brand guideline that you want
您希望代理商遵循的非常具体的品牌指南
agent to follow. Same thing here, I also
。 我也是一样，我也
have a UI design skills. They're just
有用户界面设计技能。 它们只是
one single prompt. So, all the skills
一个单一的提示。 所以，所有技能都
start with this skill.md file. Including
从这个 skill.md 文件开始。
this short description YAML explained to
这段简短的 YAML 描述向代理解释了
agent when to use this skill. And this
何时使用此技能。 该
description will always be added to the
描述将始终添加到
agent context, so it will know what kind
代理上下文中，以便代理知道
of skills it has access to. And when
自己可以使用哪些技能。 当
agent decide to call the skill, this is
代理决定调用该技能时，
where the rest of the context below will
下面的其余上下文将在此处
be loaded. So, this part almost feel
加载。 所以，这部分感觉几乎
like cloud core commands. So, skill.md
就像是云核心命令。 所以，skill.md
is the most necessary part of a skill.
是技能中最必要的部分。
For more complex skill, you can also
对于更复杂的技能，您还可以
include more resource. For example, for
投入更多资源。 例如，为了使
this skill to generate algorithm art, it
这项技能能够生成算法艺术，它还
also include resource like example
包括示例实现等资源，
implementation and get agent to read
并让代理在实现
those example reference before they
之前阅读这些示例参考，
implement to making sure we have more
以确保我们得到更
consistent result. But more importantly,
一致的结果。 但更重要的是，
you can also include some predefined
你还可以包含一些预定义的
functions. Like in this Slack GIF
函数。 就像这个 Slack GIF
creator skill, it already imported a
创建器技能一样，它已经导入了一个
package and predefined functions. And
软件包和预定义的函数。
the instruction here basically tell the
这里的指令基本上是告诉
agent how to use those functions to
代理如何使用这些功能来
create a nice GIF out of box. And here's
创建漂亮的 GIF 动画。 这就是
why I think skills might be even better
我认为技能可能
than MCPs. So, MCP has been an awesome
比 MCP 更好的原因。 因此，MCP 是
way to extend agent's capability. By
扩展代理功能的一种绝佳方式。 通过将
connecting agent with new MCPs, you can
代理与新的 MCP 连接起来，您可以
suddenly do new things that it couldn't
突然执行以前无法执行的新操作
do before. The problem is that MCP in
。 问题是，MCP在
practical is not that easy to use.
实际应用中并不那么容易。
Firstly, MCP can consume whole bunch of
首先，MCP 可能会消耗大量
tokens that is unnecessary because each
不必要的代币，因为每个
MCP can contain a bundle of different
MCP 都可以包含一系列不同的
tools. And each tool here will including
工具。 这里的每个工具都会包含
the description about when to use this
关于何时使用该
tool, as well as input schema. And all
工具的说明，以及输入方案。 无论是否有用，所有
those tokens will be loaded to agent
这些令牌都会加载到代理
context regardless whether this is
上下文中
useful or not. And more importantly,
。 更重要的是，
quite often MCP builder will want to
MCP 构建者通常希望
build the tools in a more modular way,
以更模块化的方式构建工具，
so it's reusable and more composable.
使其可重用且更易于组合。
But that also means most of MCP is not
但这也意味着 MCP 的大部分功能并不是
something you just connect and use. You
连接后就能使用的。 你
want to give agent more detailed
想给代理人更详细的
instruction about the order of when to
指示，说明何时
use which tool. And that makes setup
使用哪种工具。 这使得设置过程
more complicated. But on the other hand,
更加复杂。 但另一方面，
the way skill is set up allow you to
技能的设置方式允许你
consume much less token, but perform
消耗更少的代币，却能执行
much more complicated tasks. Let's take
更复杂的任务。 以
Chassis and MCP as example. At default,
机箱和MCP为例。 默认情况下，
it has seven different tools for
它有七种不同的工具，用于
different purpose. In fact, load the
不同的用途。 事实上，加载
context, you will see those Chassis and
上下文后，你会发现这些 Chassis 和
MCP tools already take about 4.2
MCP 工具已经占用了大约 4.2
thousand token. But you can't imagine,
千个令牌。 但你无法想象，
if we turn that into a Chassis and
如果我们把它变成一个底盘和
skill, we can probably reduce token from
技能，我们或许可以将代币数量从
4.2 thousand to just 70. And that means
4200 个减少到 70 个。这意味着
your agent can be equipped with many
你的代理可以装备
more skills and it should just work out
更多技能，而且应该
of box because skill.md can already
开箱即用，因为 skill.md 文件已经
contain all the reference instructions.
包含了所有参考指令。
Without further ado, let's show example.
事不宜迟，我们来看一个例子。
So, here under doc cloud/skills, we have
所以，在 doc cloud/skills 下，我们
loaded a list of different skills. And
加载了一个不同技能的列表。 还有
there's one skill called Slack GIF
一项名为“Slack GIF
creator, which including the
创建器”的技能，其中包括
description, the full details about how
描述、
to create a GIF, as well as some
创建 GIF 的完整细节以及一些
predefined functions. So, if I ask it to
预定义的功能。 所以，如果我让它在
create a GIF for my Slack around daily
每日站会时间前后为我的 Slack 创建一个 GIF
standup time, you will try to call this
，你会尝试使用
command Slack GIF creator with a custom
自定义提示调用此命令 Slack GIF 创建器
prompt. As I mentioned before, this
。 正如我之前提到的，这项
skill is basically reuse the command
技能本质上就是重用命令
infrastructure. If you click it yes, it
基础设施。 如果点击“是”，
will start loading all skills here. Then
就会开始加载这里的所有技能。 然后
it will create this Python code and run
它会创建并运行
this Python code, which generates GIF.
这段 Python 代码，从而生成 GIF。
It doesn't look perfect, but thing is
它看起来并不完美，但关键在于，
that it's very easy for you to think
你可以通过改进这些预定义的功能来很容易地
about how to improve this skill or
思考如何改进这项技能或
pipeline by just improving those
流程
predefined functions. There's another
。 还有一种
skill called algorithm art. If I tell it
技能叫做算法艺术。 如果我让它
to help me create animated Zen style
帮我创作禅意风格的动画
mountain algorithm art. Again, it will
山峰算法艺术。 它会再次
call this command. It will firstly
调用此命令。 它首先会
create a MD file to really design and
创建一个 MD 文件，以便真正地设计和
plan the artwork. It will read the
规划艺术作品。 它将读取
template file that we define here as
我们在这里定义为
example reference. Then it just
示例参考的模板文件。 然后它
generates animated art using P5.js.
使用 P5.js 生成动画艺术作品。
Meanwhile, another really cool thing
同时，技能的另一个非常酷的地方
about skill is that you can also start
在于，你也可以开始
using skill for your own code base as a
将技能应用到你自己的代码库中，以此来
way to make agent self-improving. So,
使智能体能够自我改进。 所以，
here's how I create skills for my own
以下是我为自己的代码库创建技能的方法
code base. So, I'm building this cloud
。 所以，我正在构建这个
platform for super design. And we have
用于超级设计的云平台。 我们有一个
this fairly large mono repo. And what I
相当大的单体仓库。 我的
do is that I load the skill creator
做法是，将技能创建器
skill inside the doc cloud folder. So, I
技能加载到文档云文件夹中。 所以，我
can give it a prompt. We have the front
可以给它一个提示。
end in this folder and also share
这个文件夹里有前端代码，共享
package here. Please go investigate our
包也在这里。 请调查一下我们
current convention and tell me what's
目前的惯例，并告诉我
the best practice for any new UI
对于任何新的 UI 组件来说，最佳实践是什么
component. Great. So, it did a quite
。 伟大的。 所以，他们进行了相当
deep investigation and come back with
深入的调查，并最终得出了
the convention. Now, let's create a
结论。 现在，让我们创建一个
skill called front end including all the
名为“前端”的技能，其中包括
implementation for our code base. Let's
我们代码库前端实现的所有最佳实践。 我们
start with how to add UI components. So,
先来看看如何添加用户界面组件。 所以，
it will try to call the skill. Initially
它会尝试调用该技能。 最初是
skill front end, which will be created
技能前端，将在
here. Including file that generates
这里创建。 包含生成
generic description. Obviously, you can
通用描述的文件。 当然，你可以
update that. Also, it start including
更新它。 此外，它还开始纳入
those best practice about our front end
有关我们前端
and UI implementation. It even created
和用户界面实现的最佳实践。 它还创建了
further reference file for the component
组件
guideline, as well as style guide. With
指南和样式指南的进一步参考文件。 有了
this one, next time if I ask it to
这个功能，下次如果我让它
create new UI component like let's
创建一个新的 UI 组件，比如
image picker in our front end, it will
在前端创建一个新的表情符号和图像选择器 UI 组件，它会
firstly call the skills to get the best
首先调用相关技能，首先
practice and coding convention in our
在我们的代码库中获取最佳实践和编码规范，
code base first and then start building
然后再
things properly following the best
按照最佳
practice. So, this is how you can use
实践正确地开始构建。 所以，这就是如何利用
skill feature to really extend agent's
技能功能来真正扩展智能体的
capability and make it continuously
能力并使其不断
improving. I just started this repo
进步的方法。 我刚刚创建了一个
called awesome cloud skills. And one of
名为“Awesome Cloud Skills”的仓库。 其中
most of them is from official cloud, but
大部分来自官方云平台，但
I start adding some stuff like UI
我开始添加一些诸如 UI
design, which including very specific
设计之类的东西，包括我一直在使用的非常具体的
prompt that I've been using. And I'll
提示。 我还会
keep adding new stuff. Also, feel free
继续添加新内容。 此外，欢迎大家
to contribute and create PRs. And
贡献代码并创建 PR。
meanwhile, if you're interested in
同时，如果您有兴趣
diving into cloud skills more, we're
深入了解云计算技能，我们将
weekly workshop at AI builder club. So,
在 AI 构建者俱乐部即将举办的每周研讨会上进行更深入的探讨。 如果您有兴趣，
you can click on the link below to join
可以点击下面的链接加入
if you're interested. I hope you enjoyed
。 希望你喜欢
this video. Thank you and I'll see you
这个视频。 谢谢，
next time.
下次再见。